Former NBAer Fined by Chinese Basketball Association
Pro basketball player Guerschon Yabusele, who played with the Boston Celtics for two seasons before moving to a professional team in China, was hit with a "serious warning"
and $1,400 fine for not looking at the Chinese flag while the country's national anthem was played before the Nanjing Tongxi Monkey Kings' game against the Zhejiang Golden Bulls last Friday.
The 23-year-old, who was born in France, says he was simply praying. He was not trying to make a political statement.
TV footage of the incident showed him with his head down with his eyes closed.
"I have the same routine every game, I've been doing this my whole career.
I just want to apologize for the people that took it personally because it was not my point," he said in a statement cited by reporters.
"In the future, I will show my respect during the Chinese national anthem and keep my head up from now on. Love you guys," he added.
The Chinese Basketball Association handbook dictates that players must look at the flag while "March of the Volunteers," the Chinese anthem, is played.
It's also a crime in China to show disrespect to the national anthem.